Chicago, USA Linkedin

#### Jacopo Scrinzi

(331) 254 9852 scrinzi.jacopo@gmail.com

I'm a pragmatic software engineer with nearly a decade of expertise in designing, developing, and securing applications running in AWS. I spent the past six years securing Intercom Ruby on Rails monolith, collaborating with teams on risk mitigation and developing infrastructure & application security controls.

#### **Work Experience**

# Staff Software EngineerIntercomOct 2022 - PresentCloud Security TeamChicago, USA

- Led the Cloud Security team strategy enabling a re-org and influencing the team's yearly roadmap. Delegated projects and provided planning and execution support. Mentored peers and enabled them to take on more complex projects, increasing team productivity by 60%.
- Substantially contributed to the security risk management program. Discovered new risks through threat models and security reviews. Defined mitigations and discussed them with a diverse group of engineers, managers and directors. Supported teams with the execution.
- Mitigated highest risk owned by the Cloud Security team by implementing security controls to ensure the safety and integrity of Intercom's attachments feature used by millions of people.
- Mitigated active credential stuffing attacks by developing a reputational based ReCAPTCHA on Intercom's sign-in page. Introduced customer notifications, informing them of suspicious logins to the Intercom application – reduced account takeover attack disruptions by 30%.
- Increased the pool of people responding to security incidents by 50%, addressing engineering burnout concerns. Improved training material and introduced game-days & tabletop exercises.

# Senior Software EngineerIntercomApr 2020 - Oct 2022Security TeamChicago, USA

- Migrated SIEM from StreamAlert to Panther, eliminating the operational cost, allowing the team to focus on enhancing detections and onboarding more data sources improved detection and investigation capabilities by 300%.
- Enhanced Intercom's threat detection capabilities by deploying Crowdstrike as an EDR solution to all Intercom's endpoints and integrating AWS GuardDuty with Panther.
- Managed Intercom's Bug Bounty program and incorporated it in the on-call process. Reviewed and rewarded findings, and worked with the teams to address them effectively.

# Software EngineerIntercomFeb 2018 - Apr 2020Security TeamDublin, Ireland & Chicago, USA

- Introduced the Infrastructure-as-Code program at Intercom (Terraform). Developed a CI/CD pipeline enabling hundreds of engineers to safely make changes to the production environment.
- Developed a distributed malware scanner solution for customer supplied files which performs on average over 1 million scans daily and removes malicious content from Intercom's CDN.
- Developed data deleters in Intercom's Ruby on Rails monolith to meet GDPR compliance.

Systems Engineer	Intercom	June 2016 - Feb 2018
Infrastructure Team	Dublin, Ireland	
Systems Engineer	Anacapa Holdings, Ltd.	Jan 2015 - June 2016

#### **Education**